in today's tutorial we're looking at how
to do a Russian join this is an easy way
to join two pieces of yarn that doesn't
require any knots or weaving in ends
let's jump right in and take a look at
how it
works so I'm going to begin by cutting
just some fresh tail ends which will
make the whole process a little bit
easier now let's just say that this
darker blue end is the project that I'm
working on this is the yarn that's
attached to the project I'm working on
and then this lighter blue end is the
yarn that I want to add in and so I'm
going to start with the dark blue
end and I'm just going to get the yarn
on the needle
there and now what I'm going to do is
leave just a little bit of a tail
end and then I'm going to into the
working end of the yarn I am going to
run my blunt yarn needle in between the
Plies of
yarn and so you can see
here that if you just gingerly move the
needle through the center of the strand
of
yarn you go right through the PES of the
yarn it's worth noting that this
technique does not work well for unpi
Yarns so that would be any yarn that
doesn't have a Twist to it examples of
unied yarn are roving wool Chenille um
anything that's like faux for it
wouldn't work for those
Yarns you don't want to do this for too
far because this method does add a
little bit of bulk to the join area of
the
[Music]
join so once we've got about that much
what we want to do is just carefully
pull the tail end through so I going
to get the tail end you can see it's
kind of in the middle of that Loop there
the loop is what we're looking for okay
so I'm going to pinch right along here
and just pull the tail end
through now once you can get it
out just go ahead and set down this
side we'll leave that Loop just right
there okay so now we're going to thread
the other tail
end now before I go ahead what we're
going to do is do the same thing with
this side but the first thing I need to
do is thread this yarn through this
Loop so we're just going to bring it
through okay so now I've got my loose
end on this side and then this is the
working end of the yarn and so I'm going
to take the blunt yarn needle and go
through the working end of the yarn
and we're going to do the same thing
where we just carefully work right
through the middle of the yarn just
separating the strands the pies of yarn
with the blunt yarn needle
okay great that looks like enough and so
now I'm just going to carefully pull the
needle through
again feels like this side is The Tail
End maybe
nope there we
go okay now we're going to get the
needle off of
there now you can kind of see what going
on here so what I'm going to do at this
point is I am going to tighten the tail
ends of both sides and that's going to
join them together really
neatly so just pinching up that gather
of yarn
there pulling the tail end nice and
top and again with the opposite side
[Music]
okay and now at this point what you can
do just smooth out the PES that you
gathered and you can see that is a nice
tight joint of yarn that's not going to
come undone and it's not too much more
bulky than the actual strand of yarn it
is a bit but not by much so at this
point you can see the tail ends are
still just sort of dangling there and
all you need to do is trim
them the edge of where you trim the
Tails is going to be the bulkiest part
of this
okay guys so that is the Russian join if
you found this helpful please don't
forget to like And subscribe I will see
you in the next video